# **Shalini Choudhary**

# **SEO Manager**

#### MY APPROACH TO WORK

My experience in SEO spans over 7+ years, and I have worked with companies of all sizes on Search Engine Optimization (SEO) tactics. I believe that there is no such thing as a "one size fits all" solution when it comes to SEO, so I tailor my approach to each client based on their goals and needs.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## SEO Manager

02/2022 - Present

### Global University Systems

Gurugram, HR

GUS is a network of institutions, affiliates and partners that offer globally-respected courses and qualifications to students from all corners of the world.

- 100% Increase in organic ranking of keywords in Top 10 position within 12 months.
- Developing and implementing long-term SEO strategies that align with the organization's overall business objectives.
- Identifying new opportunities for growth generation through SEO and making data-driven recommendations to senior leadership.
- Collaborating with cross-functional teams, including content creators, web developers, and graphic designers, to optimize website content and design for search engines.
- Defining KPIs for SEO and developing a measurement framework to track and report on performance to key stakeholders.

## SEO Manager

11/2019 - 01/2022

GroupM

Gurugram, HR

GroupM is the world's leading media investment company.

- Brands Handled Dabur, Zee5, Kurkure, Royal Enfield & more.
- Dabur Group SEO for 3 product websites and overall 20% increase in non-branded traffic.
- Zee 5 Content Strategy & Marketing Integrating a top to bottom-of-the funnel approach
  to increase organic traffic, boost brand awareness, drive subscriptions and user retention
  on the platform, aligning with the brand's values and audience preferences.
- Driving SEO campaign growth of clients by suggesting future roadmap of opportunities.

## Digital Marketing Analyst

02/2019 - 10/2019

J LL

Gurugram,HR

- Collaborated with digital team on daily revisions to page content, pictures, and videos, resulting in 15% higher visitor traction.
- Hands-on working on AEM (Adobe Experience Manager) platform for rolling out changes on webpages.
- Conducting comprehensive keyword research to identify high-traffic and high-converting keywords to target.
- Pre and post lauch check of websites/subdomains rolling out in different regions across the globe.

# SEO Analyst

09/2016 - 01/2019

#### Ogilvy & Mather Pvt. Ltd.

Gurugram, HR

- · Brands Handled Spencers, Fortune Foods, Mphasis, Dove, & more.
- Analyzing competitors' websites, client website traffic, and performance metrics to identify trends, patterns, and areas for improvement.
- Developing and implementing SEO strategies to improve website rankings and traffic, including on-page optimization, content optimization, and link-building strategies.
- Managing and tracking website performance using tools such as Google Analytics, Search Console, and other SEO software.
- Creating reports and presentations to communicate SEO performance metrics and recommendations to stakeholders.



#### **SKILLS**

#### Standard Software

Excel · Word · Powerpoint · Outlook

#### **Analytics & SEO Tools**

Google Analytics •

Google Search Console · SEMRush ·

Ahrefs · Moz · Screaming Frog

#### Product-led SEO

User centric Content & SEO Strategy

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

√ 7+ Years SEO Experience

And it still feels interesting



Conducted for all kind of websites

#### **EDUCATION**

#### LinkedIn Learning

- <u>Technical SEO</u> By Dana DiTomaso
- <u>SEO: Keyword Strategy</u> By Matt Bailey

#### Master in Media Studies

Haridev Joshi University of Journalism & Mass Communication - Jaipur, RJ

### Bachelor of Business Administration

Maharani's College - Jaipur, RJ

# Higher Secondary

Children's Academy (ISC Board) - Jaipur,

#### Senior Secondary

Children's Academy (ICSE Board) -Jaipur, RJ